A Finding Aid to the William Mills Ivins Papers, 1878-1964, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Professional and Personal Papers, circa 1908-1961; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-8; 6.5 linear ft.)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, circa 1908-1961; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Osborne, William Church, 1925-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
      (about MMA administration and policy; writings of WMI; WMI's recommendations for Bulletin)
    - Correspondence, P, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10-15)
      (includes: Pach, Walter, 1921-1955; Phillips, Duncan, 1929-1930; Print Club of Cleveland, 1923-1945; Print Club (of Philadelphia Pa.), 1925-1926; Print Club of Rochester, 1931-1932; Print Collectors Quarterly, 1922-1924; Print Makers Society of California, 1921)
    - Panofsky, Erwin, 1932-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Pease, Murray, 1945-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Quartich, Bernard, 1918-1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
      (invoices and letters concerning purchases of books for WMI personal library)
    - Correspondence, R, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19-22)
      (includes: Rorimer, James, 1934-1961; Rosenbach, A.S.W., 1931; Rosenberg, Jakob, 1927-1953)
    - Redmond, Rollin, 1944-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Riggs, Lawrason, 1933-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Robinson, Edward, 1917-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 25)
      (about MMA Print Dept.; other museum business, including loans and exhibitions; travels)
    - Rogers, Bruce, 1919-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Rollins, Carl Purington, and Margaret, 1931-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 27)
      (about WMI writings; samples of printing; and news of mutual friends)
    - Rosenthal, [Rabbi] Henry M., 1945-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 28-30)
    - Rous, Peyton, 1945-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Ruzicka, Rudolph, 1917-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 32)
      (about his exhibitions; travels; printing; exhibition design; WMI's writings; news of mutual friends)
    - Correspondence, S, Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 33-39)
      (includes Schniewind, Carl O., 1930-1946; Sheeler, Charles. undated; Spicer-Simson, Theodore, 1944; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1928-1929)
    - Sachs, Paul J., and Meta, 1910-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
      (about Fogg Art Museum; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston; acquisitions; PJS lectures; WMI writings and lectures; prints and drawings on the market; travels)
    - Sarton, George, 1942-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 42)
      (about philosophy, ancient and modern; books; Isis (Review of the History and Philosophy of Science); WMI's writings)
    - Saunders, A.P., 1942-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Savile Club, 1933-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Simkhovitch, Vladimir G., 1918-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
      (about art; history of ancient Greece; WMI's writings)
    - Simonson, Lee, 1929-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)
      (about books and reading; WMI's writings; teaching; opera set designs; news of mutual friends)
    - Singer, Charles Joseph, 1949-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5)
      (WMI criticism of CS writings on Vesalius; books; anatomy; writings of WMI)
    - Sizer, Theodore, 1922-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
      (WMI lectures to Cleveland Print Club; travels; news of mutual friends; exhibitions; Yale University Art Gallery; TS lectures and book on Trumbull)
    - Southold [Long Island] property, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Stechert, G.E. & Co., 1909-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 11)
      (invoices and letters regarding purchase of books for WMI library)
    - Stowaways, 1921-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence, T, Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14-17)
    - Taylor, Francis Henry, 1933-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 18)
      (about MMA business; WMI lectures)
    - Troxell, Janet, 1954-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
    - Correspondence, U, Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - University of Chicago, 1932-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
      (includes U.C. Press)
    - Correspondence, V, Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
    - Vasari Society, 1922-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, W, Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26-32)
      (includes: Watrous, Harry W., 1925; Watson, Forbes, 1926)
    - Wallace, Ed, 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Warburg, Felix M., 1919-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 34)
      (about acquisitions for FMW collection)
    - Webster, Herman A., and Mounette, 1910-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 35)
      (Folders 35-36 about travels; prints for sale in Europe; WMI's writings; exhibitions of HAW work in U.S.; German occupation of France)
    - Webster, Herman A., and Mounette, circa 1948-circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Weil, Ernst, 1932-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 37)
      (about WMI book purchases; see also: Tauber & Weil)
    - Wetmore, Edith, 1928-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Weyhe, E., 1948-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 39)
      (about WMI book purchases)
    - Wilkinson, Charles, 1946-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 40)
      (about MMA staff; travels; news of mutual friends)
    - Wind, Edgar, 1945-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
      (about Vesalius; translations; Greek art; aesthetics; his own writings and those of WMI; news of mutual friends)
    - Winlock, Herbert Eustis, 1931-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
      (about MMA staff; MMA Egyptian expedition; acquisitions; MMA administration)
    - Winter, Carl, 1939-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
      (about Elizabethan miniatures; World War II; book about Nicholas Hilliard; news of mutual friends)
    - Winternitz, Emanuel, 1945-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
      (about MMA staff; MMA Musical Instrument Collection; news of mutual friends)
    - Woodbury, Conn. Property, 1941-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Woodhouse, Betty Burroughs, 1935-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Y, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
      (includes Young, Art, undated)
    - Yale University, 1942-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
      (includes Art GalleryConvocation, 1946; Elizabethan Club; Library; Y.U. Press; Yale Review)
    - Correspondence, Z, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
      (includes Zigrosser, Carl, 1932-1959)
    - Correspondence, unknown and illegible, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, Correspondence and Office Files, circa 1919-1947; 1.2; Archival Resource Key
    The file on European travels contains letters of introduction to curators and collectors, miscellaneous notes, and expense records for museum business. Files on gifts and loans refer to those from WMI's personal collection to the museum. Metropolitan Museum Studies files include records of the Editorial board meetings, 1927-1936; circulation records, 1933; general records, 1931; Vol 4 and 5, 1933-1935; correspondence with and about contributors, including Burroughs, Alan, Cooke, Walter W.S., Cumont, Diamond, W., Dinsmore, William B., Frick, Colin G., Jacobsthal, Lewis, W.S., Morgan, John Hill, Panofsky, Erwin, Planiscig, L., Richter, Gisela A.M., Tietze, Hans, Updike, D.B., and Wehle, H; and rejected articles. Printed matter does not include exhibition catalogs from the museum.
    - Addresses, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
    - Calendar, 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Employees' Association, 1937-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - European Travels, 1919, 1922; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Gifts, 1922-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Loans, 1923-1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, Notes, etc., 1923-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Pension, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Printed Material Issued by Metropolitan Museum, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Print Department, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Publications, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Restaurant Bills, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Durer Collection of Junius Spencer Morgan, circa 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
    - Metropolitan Museum Studies, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28-50)
    - Clippings, Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - History of Metropolitan Museum of Art by Winifred E. Howe, 1905-1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
      (galley sheets annotated by WMI)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, 1932-1958; 1.3; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries relates to major publications and is filed by title in chronological order. Additional correspondence regarding Ivins' publications is included in the alphabetical sequence, usually filed under the name of editor, rather than publisher or periodical.
    - On the Rationalization of Sight, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Three Vesalian Essays, University of Chicago and New York Academy of Medicine, 1932-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Art & Geometry, Harvard University Press and Routledge & Kegan Paul, Ltd., 1945-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Prints and Visual Communication, Harvard University Press and Routledge & Kegan Paul, Ltd., 1950-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - What Makes a Masterpiece?, Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Writings, circa 1910-1960; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 8-12; 4.9 linear ft.)
  Arrangement
  As far as possible the records are arranged in chronological order.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of notes, drafts, manuscripts, and corrected gallery sheets for books, articles, reviews, lectures, etc., by William M. Ivins, Jr., both published and unpublished. Some are in notebooks spanning several years and covering a range of topics, in no apparent order within the volumes. Also included are autobiographical notes, circa 1925-1950's, and leaves from diaries dated 1919 and 1943-1945. Many are untitled and undated.
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Articles and Lectures, circa 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Notes, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Daumier, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Museum Aesthetics, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Notes- Pling, Aesthetics Theory, Etc., circa 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Books and Prints, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Notebook, circa 1927-1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Notebook, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Notebook, circa 1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Notebook, circa 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Bryson Burroughs, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Morgan Library lectures, "Aspects of Renaissance Book Illustration", circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31-35)
  - Morgan Library lectures, "Aspects of Renaissance Book Illustration", circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-7)
  - Morgan Library Lectures, Illustrated Books, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Morgan Library Lectures, Corrected Typescript, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Morgan Library Lectures, Miscellaneous, circa 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "On the Rationalization of Sight", 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Free Thought in the Country", 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Peter Bruegel- Lables for Exhibitions", 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "Mathematics and the Imagination", 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Art and Geometry", 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Yale Convocation, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "A Note on Ipseity", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Manuscript Fallacies", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7-11)
  - "Fakes", 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
  - "What About the Fabrica of Vesalius?", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14-16)
  - Book Review, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Some Disconnected Notes About Drawing", 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Book Review, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - "A Neglected Aspect of Early Print Making", 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, late 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Lefebvre Des Noettes", 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
  - Lowell Lectures, "Prints and Visual Communications", circa 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26-30)
  - Lowell Lectures, "Prints and Visual Communications", circa 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1-7)
  - Lowell Lectures, "Record of Photography", circa 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lowell Lectures, "Malraux La Psycholygie de l' Art", circa 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
  - Lowell Lectures, Miscellaneous, circa 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Masterpieces", 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Prints- Technique and Expression", 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1952- circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
  - Meditations, 1940s- 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, circa late 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Autobiographical Notes, circa 1950s; circa 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Early Museum Period, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22-25)
  - Early Museum Period, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Early Bulletin Articles, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, circa 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 6-9)
  - Articles, etc., late 1920s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Drafts of Published Writings #1, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous from Woodbury Study, circa 1949-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Geometrical Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Notes on Book Illustrations, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - "Perspective", 1910-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Notes on American Prints, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Notes on Early Etching, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Vesalius", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21-27)
- Publications, 1896-1958; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 2 Linear feet Boxes 13-14
  This series contains an incomplete set of publications by Ivins including books, articles, lectures, exhibition catalogs, and reviews. Many are marked copies, corrected or otherwise annotated by the author. When available, reviews of books and exhibitions are filed with the corresponding volume. The first folder in the series contrains Ivin's first published work, consisting of letters written to his mother while in South America.
  The publications are arranged in chronological order by date of publication, while later editions are reprints filed by date of first publication.
  - "A Trip Worth Describing, Letters from a Lad While Traveling," Monmouth Democrat [Freehold, N.J.], 1896 December 3; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Catalogue of an Exhibition of Prints by Albrecht Durer, With an Introduction by William M. Ivins, Jr.," Frederick Keppel &Co., 1917 November 5-31; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Wood Engravings by Rudolph Ruzicka, Newark Public Library, 1917 March 5-31; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition of Painter Etchings and Engravings of the XIX Century, Consisting Mainly of Loans From Private Collections, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1917 April; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Wood Engravings of Rudolph Ruzicka, The Newark Museum Association, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - A Catalogue of Italian Renaissance Woodcuts, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "Of Museums," The Arts, vol. III, no. 1, 1923 January; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - "Daumier- The Man of His Time," The Arts, vol. III, no. 2, Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Loan Exhibition of the Italian Renaissance, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1923 May 7- September 9; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "A History of Engraving and Etching, by Arthur M. Hind." Reviewed by Ivins in The Literary Review, 1935 July 21; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - "A Note on Claude Garamond, Punch- Cutter & Type- Founder," in Monotype, vol. 9, no. 6, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - A Guide to an Exhibition of The Arts of the Book, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1924 May 12- September 14; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Goya's Disasters of War," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XIX, no. 9, 1924 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "A Gift of Prints," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XX, no. 8, Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - "Joseph Pennell," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXI, no. 11, 1925 August; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Prints and Books, Informal Papers, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "Photography and the 'Modern' Point of View, A Speculation in the History of Taste," Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. I, pt. 1, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - "A Note Apropos of Two Anniversaries," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXII, no. 1, 1928 January; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - "A Collection of English Trading Cards," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXIII, no. 2, 1928 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - "Beauty in the Architecture," The Arts, vol. XIV, no. 3, 1928 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - "Philbert de l'Orme's Premiere Tome de l'architecture," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXIV, no. 5, 1929 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - "Notes on Three Durer Woodblocks," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. II, pt. 1, 1929 November; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - "Kleiner's Residences Memorables," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXIV, no. 12, 1929 December 12; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - "Vasari's Lives," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - "Notes on Two Woodcuts of the Nuremberg School," Metropolitan Museum Studies, vol. II, pt 3, 1930 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Notes on Prints, Being the Text of Labels Prepared for a Special Exhibition of Prints from the Museum Collection, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "French Eighteenth-Century Engravings," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXVI, no. 2, 1931 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Daumier, 1931 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - "An Exhibition of Reproductive Prints," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXVI, no. 10, 1931 October; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - "Early Woodcuts," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXVII, no. 2, 1932 February; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - "Address at the Cooper Union, Tuesday, 25th of February 1932", 1932 February 25; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Hugh Thompson- His Art, His Letters, His Humor, and His Charm by M.H. Spielmann and Walter Jerrold, reviewed by Ivins in The Saturday Review of Literature, vol. IX, no. 1, 1932 July 23; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - "Artistic Aspects of Fifteenth-Century Printing," Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, vol. XXVI, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - "An Undescribed Schongauer Trial Proof," Metropolitan Museum Studies, vol. IV, pt. 2, 1933 March; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - "Two Woodcuts of the Virgin," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXVII, no. 4, 1932 April; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - "A Woodblock by Brueghel," Metropolitan Museum Studies, vol. V, pt. 1, 1934 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - "On Education in a Museum," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, vol. XXIX, no. 9, 1934 September; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Bryson Burroughs, Catalogue of a Memorial Exhibition of his Works, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1935 March 25- May 5; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Francisco Goya, His Paintings, Drawings, and Prints, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1936 January 27- March 8; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 39)